<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-09T23:51:56-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">idemeum.github.io</title><entry><title type="html">How secure is idemeum?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/idemeum-security" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How secure is idemeum?" /><published>2021-01-07T16:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-07T16:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/idemeum-security</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/idemeum-security">&lt;h2 id=&quot;security-as-part-of-our-mission&quot;&gt;Security as part of our mission&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to make digital identity private, secure, and simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security is one of the core principles that is applied to everything we do - mobile, backend, DevOps, it does not matter, security is fundamental and key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is more, authentication is mission critical to businesses and individuals. Therefore, we designed idemeum in accordance with the latest best practices as it relates to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_security&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CIA triad of confidentiality, integrity, and availability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;security-starts-with-people&quot;&gt;Security starts with people&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;idemeum team brings together years of cybersecurity experience, and we have top mobile, backend, and network security engineers. We have expertise working for the largest Fortune 500 companies across high tech and financial sector.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;standardized-security-processes&quot;&gt;Standardized security processes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are conducting continuous threat modeling and evaluation to make sure we harden idemeum even further. idemeum builds security into each step of our operations, including code release, upgrades, patch management, security policies and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;security-by-design&quot;&gt;Security by design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;idemeum backend&lt;/strong&gt; we have taken a radical new approach by storing your personal data on your mobile device only. What that means is that we have no users’ digital identity data in our backend. Not only is it important from the privacy standpoint, but it also reduces attack surface significantly. If our backend gets compromised, attackers will get nothing from it, as there is not valuable user data there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a &lt;strong&gt;mobile side&lt;/strong&gt;, we are following general mobile security best practices, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://owasp.org/www-project-mobile-security/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OWASP Mobile Top 10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, in order to protect idemeum mobile application. We leverage security measures such as hardware based key encryption, jailbreak detection, data encryption, liveness detection and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;idemeum leverages &lt;strong&gt;biometric based authentication&lt;/strong&gt; that is using biometric sensors on iOS and Android mobile devices. We are using FIDO2 protocol (developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://fidoalliance.org&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FIDO Alliance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) that is becoming the de-facto standard in the identity industry. The FIDO Alliance developed FIDO Authentication standards based on public key cryptography for authentication that is more secure than passwords and SMS OTPs, simpler for consumers to use, and easier for service providers to deploy and manage. FIDO Authentication enables password-only logins to be replaced with secure and fast login experiences across websites and apps. For public-key cryptography idemeum keeps only the public key on our servers and stores private keys on your devices in a tamper-proof secure element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more, &lt;a href=&quot;https://idemeum.com/contact&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;contact idemeum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; so that we can show you a quick demo and tell you more about our product.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nikolay</name></author><summary type="html">Security as part of our mission</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why did we make idemeum verified?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/idemeum-verification" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why did we make idemeum verified?" /><published>2021-01-06T16:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-06T16:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/idemeum-verification</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/idemeum-verification">&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-do-we-need-to-verify-digital-identity&quot;&gt;Why do we need to verify digital identity?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identity plays a major role in everyday life. It’s the key that determines the particular transactions in which we can rightfully participate as well as the information we’re entitled to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in a world that’s increasingly governed by digital transactions and data, our existing methods for verifying someone’s identity are far from adequate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;
  In 2019 alone financial losses due to identity fraud totaled $1.9B
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the meme “On the Internet, nobody knows you’re a dog”? It was drawn by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/On_the_Internet,_nobody_knows_you're_a_dog&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peter Steiner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and published by The New Yorker on July 5, 1993. It is still as true today as ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blogs/idemeum-verified/idog.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cartoon implies the ability to send and receive messages — or to create and maintain a website — behind a mask of anonymity. “Nobody knows” is there because Internet protocols require no user to confirm or prove one’s own identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are situations where identity proofing is not required or is even undesirable (use cases where anonymity or pseudonymity is required), there are others where it is important to reliably establish an association with a real-life subject. Examples include obtaining health care or executing financial transactions. There are also situations where the association is required for regulatory reasons (the financial industry’s ‘Know Your Customer’ requirements, established in the implementation of the USA PATRIOT Act of 2001) or to establish accountability for high-risk actions (changing the release rate of water from a dam).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;When accessing some low-risk digital services, “being a dog” is just fine; while other, high-risk services need a level of confidence that the digital identity accessing the service is the legitimate proxy to the real-life subject.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-do-we-verify-digital-identity&quot;&gt;When do we verify digital identity?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer this question let’s take a look at the simplistic diagram of identity lifecycle and get some terminology in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blogs/idemeum-verified/identity-lifecycle.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I can access any service, I need to prove my identity so that a credential can be created, and I can be enrolled as valid subject within the identity system. Therefore, &lt;strong&gt;identity proofing&lt;/strong&gt; is all about establishing that an applicant is who they claim to be. At this point I will also create an authenticator (password, PIN, certificate, etc.) that will be linked to my digital identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I return to the service, I need to provide reasonable risk-based assurance that I am the same person who previously accessed the service. Hence, &lt;strong&gt;authentication&lt;/strong&gt; establishes that a subject attempting to access a digital service is in control of one or more valid authenticators associated with the subject’s digital identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, once I am authenticated, the service needs to know what privileges I can be granted. &lt;strong&gt;Authorization&lt;/strong&gt; helps with that, as it is the process of giving the user permission to access a specific resource or function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;So, identity proofing typically happens at &quot;before&quot; phase. However, it would be also useful to extend the trust all the way to &quot;during&quot; phase, so that when the user returns to the service, we not only assure that he has a valid authenticator in possession and control, but also assure his identity.&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-identity-verification-work&quot;&gt;How does identity verification work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When identity proofing is done, it needs to be done at a certain “Identity Assurance Level (IAL)”. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; sets requirements for each of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.nist.gov/800-63-3/sp800-63a.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3 levels&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, based on the required security level and assumed risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity Assurance Level 1 (IAL1)&lt;/strong&gt;: There is no requirement to link the applicant to a specific real-life identity. Any attributes provided in conjunction with the authentication process are self-asserted or should be treated as such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity Assurance Level 2 (IAL2)&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence supports the real-world existence of the claimed identity and verifies that the applicant is appropriately associated with this real-world identity. IAL2 introduces the need for either remote or physically-present identity proofing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity Assurance Level 3 (IAL3)&lt;/strong&gt;: Physical presence is required for identity proofing. Identifying attributes must be verified by an authorized and trained representative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process of identity verification is progressing across 3 phase. First, the document and additional context need to be &lt;strong&gt;collected&lt;/strong&gt;. Second, the supplied information is &lt;strong&gt;validated&lt;/strong&gt; to make sure the documents are valid, not expired, or forged, etc.. And finally, the identity is &lt;strong&gt;verified&lt;/strong&gt; by matching the document with the photo supplied by the subject. At this phase, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.liveness.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;liveness detection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is typically performed to make sure the system is interfacing with a physically present human being and not an inanimate spoof artifact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;where-do-we-do-identity-verification&quot;&gt;Where do we do identity verification?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote identity proofing services are becoming more and more prevalent across online services. Service owners, especially in the financial industry, are integrating identity verification product in order to minimize the impact of ID fraud, which has been steadily increasing recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, things are quite different on the enterprise identity side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;
  71% of surveyed enterprises reported password lockout issues and sign-in challenges
  &lt;footer class=&quot;blockquote-footer mt-3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hitachi-id.com/cgi-bin/emaildoc?document=identity-and-access-management-trends-during-covid-19.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hitachi ID survey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enterprises are still leveraging insecure methods as it relates to digital identity onboarding and proofing. Credentials are distributed over email or SMS, or often times managers print them and distribute physically. Even when magic links or one times tokens are used instead of passwords, those are still relying on email for distribution. Think about it - when someone clicks on that magic link or uses one-time password, how do we know that is a real employee and not some hacker?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;
  Enterprises have no way of knowing the identity of employee they are providing access to systems and critical resources.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;idemeum-can-help&quot;&gt;idemeum can help&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;idemeum solves the problem of insecure employee enrollment by providing built-in identity verification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blogs/idemeum-verified/verification.png&quot; style=&quot;width: 40%;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With idemeum app users can upload the ID document and their photo and quickly verify digital identity. idemeum follows IAL level 2 NIST recommendations. As a result of the verification, all verified identity claims are stored on a mobile device only. No PII is maintained or stored in the idemeum backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;
  idemeum does not store any user identifiable information in the backend.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that idemeum extends the identity trust beyond just initial identity verification and enrollment. Every time the user authenticates or accesses corporate resources, the identity is assured using idemeum app. Therefore, enterprises can have an assurance that only verified and legitimate user are accessing the resources, and not some hackers who gained access to issues authenticators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to learn more, &lt;a href=&quot;https://idemeum.com/contact&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;contact idemeum&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; so that we can show you a quick demo.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nikolay</name></author><summary type="html">Why do we need to verify digital identity?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why did we make idemeum decentralized?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/about-privacy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why did we make idemeum decentralized?" /><published>2021-01-05T16:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-05T16:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/about-privacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/about-privacy">&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-is-digital-identity-evolving&quot;&gt;How is digital identity evolving?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today digital identity is typically managed at enterprise or application level. What that means is that when you sign up for a service or get hired by a company, your digital identity is created for you, and it is stored at a centralized database owned by a service provider. To access service or corporate resources, we have to prove our digital identity by presenting username / password combination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blogs/about-privacy/centralized-identity-model.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;centralized model&lt;/strong&gt; is not convenient for us users - we have to constantly create accounts and memorize numerous password combinations. Moreover, these central databases become honeypots for attackers, who target these databases with persistence and advanced tools in order to steal our personal information and monetize it by committing identity fraud or selling it on a dark web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;“Today’s digital identity frameworks are centralized, suffer from a lack of trust, aren’t portable, and don’t give consumers control.”
&lt;footer class=&quot;blockquote-footer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forrester.com/report/New+Tech+Decentralized+Digital+Identity+DDID+Q1+2020/-/E-RES147115&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Forrester research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time centralized model is not desirable for service providers - credentials get compromised and lead to costly cyber breaches, or they simply get forgotten which leads to password resets and costly support calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, industry moved to a &lt;strong&gt;federated&lt;/strong&gt; identity model where a single party becomes in charge of creating and managing digital identities for a group of different enterprises and services. The most used federation providers are Google and Facebook, where you can use your social network account to log in and sign up for other services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Federated model provides better user experience, however it has similar drawbacks. Federated model creates massive pools of data that can be monetized and also serve as a central point of failure. With federated model users have no control over their digital identity since they do not know what data is exactly collected and what it is used for. A recent example is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook–Cambridge_Analytica_data_scandal&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cambridge Analytica scandal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; where Facebook gave unfettered and unauthorized access to personally identifiable information (PII) of more than 87 million Facebook users without their consent to the data firm Cambridge Analytica.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-made-idemeum-decentralized&quot;&gt;We made idemeum decentralized&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We built idemeum to be &lt;strong&gt;decentralized&lt;/strong&gt; so that we can enable 100% user privacy. idemeum removes the need for a central trusted authority. Users store their digital identity on mobile devices and decide what and with who they want to share their personal information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at how idemeum if different from centralized and federated models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control&lt;/strong&gt;: with idemeum you have full control of your digital identity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User experience&lt;/strong&gt;: idemeum simplifies sign-in and sign-up experience. No more passwords to type, and no more lengthy forms to fill out - access the service with a click of a button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;: security is way better with idemeum as users are no longer using passwords, and enterprises are no longer maintaining centralized honeypots of PII information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fraud&lt;/strong&gt;: idemeum reduces identity fraud as there are no more credentials and passwords to re-use.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Portability&lt;/strong&gt;: with idemeum your digital identity is portable. You can bring our identity to a new place of work, or use it when signing up for a new service. No need to constantly recreate your digital self.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-idemeum-enable-100-privacy&quot;&gt;How does idemeum enable 100% privacy?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first principle of idemeum is “privacy by design”. We do not store any PII information in our backend. Let’s take a look at some high level technical information to understand how idemeum works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you create your idemeum on a digital device, you are assigned a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.w3.org/TR/did-core/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralized Identifier (DID)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that uniquely represents your digital identity among others. You DID is a globally unique persistent identifier that does not require a centralized registration authority because it is generated and registered cryptographically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blogs/about-privacy/decentralized-idemeum.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;idemeum also generates an asymmetric cryptographic key pair that will be unique for your digital identity. Also known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public-key_cryptography&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;public-key cryptography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this style of cryptography uses a public key to encrypt data that can only be decrypted with a paired private key. Public key, which can be known to public, is stored in idemeum backend and is associated with your DID. Private key, which must be kept secret, is safely stored on your mobile device and is protected by hardware based security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;idemeum uses asymmetric cryptography to authenticate your identity. When you log in to an online resource, idemeum backend sends your app a challenge with the request to sign it with your private key. By scanning your biometric with idemeum app you automatically unlock your private key, sign the requested challenge, and send it back to our backend. This way we can always know that you are who you claim to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No passwords needed - instead we leverage the power of asymmetric cryptography and biometric based authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blogs/about-privacy/authn.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you create your idemeum profile and add identity claims such as phone number, email address, or ID document, all information is safely stored on your mobile device only. We not no store any of your personal information in our backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-primary&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;
  idemeum is a decentralized identity platform - we do not store any of your personal information in our cloud. We fundamentally believe in digital identity privacy, and we made idemeum to be private-by-design.
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Nikolay</name></author><summary type="html">How is digital identity evolving?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">idemeum is how people identify themselves online</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/about-idemeum" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="idemeum is how people identify themselves online" /><published>2021-01-04T16:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2021-01-04T16:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/about-idemeum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/about-idemeum">&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-12 mx-auto&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h6 class=&quot;text-uppercase&quot;&gt;About the name&lt;/h6&gt;
        &lt;h3 class=&quot;display-3&quot;&gt;What does idemeum mean?&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row mt-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6 mx-auto&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Let's start with the name. We wanted the name of the product to reflect our mission and what we stand for.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;idemeum is comprised of two latin words: &lt;i&gt;meum&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;idem&lt;/i&gt; that mean &quot;my&quot; and  &quot;identity&quot;.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;We aspire idemeum to be truly yours. Something that you can own, control, and share only with people and services you choose to. And we want idemeum to be your digital identity. Not some random string of characters that is hard to remember, but your true digital identity that you can use personally and professionally.
        &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6 mx-auto&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;card card-blog card-background&quot; data-animation=&quot;zooming&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;full-background&quot; style=&quot;background-image: url('/assets/img/blogs/about-idemeum/my-name.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;card-body&quot;&gt;
            &lt;div class=&quot;content-bottom&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3 class=&quot;card-title text-white&quot;&gt;identity (n.)&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p class=&quot;card-description text-white&quot;&gt;The word identity was first used in English by bishop and historian John Bale in 1545. Through Middle French, it all comes from the Latin neuter idem, meaning &quot;the same&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;a class=&quot;btn btn-primary btn-sm&quot; href=&quot;https://www.etymonline.com/word/identity&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-12 mx-auto&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h6 class=&quot;text-uppercase&quot;&gt;What's in it for you?&lt;/h6&gt;
      &lt;h3 class=&quot;display-3&quot;&gt;How can you use idemeum?&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row mt-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-4 align-items-stretch d-flex justify-content-center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;card bg-gradient-primary&quot; style=&quot;width: 20rem;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;card-body&quot;&gt;
            &lt;h5 class=&quot;card-title text-white&quot;&gt;Login without passwords&lt;/h5&gt;
            &lt;p class=&quot;card-description text-white&quot;&gt;Use phone with biometric sensor to access online resources.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-4 align-items-stretch d-flex justify-content-center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;card bg-gradient-primary&quot; style=&quot;width: 20rem;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;card-body&quot;&gt;
            &lt;h5 class=&quot;card-title text-white&quot;&gt;Verify identity&lt;/h5&gt;
            &lt;p class=&quot;card-description text-white&quot;&gt;Access and sign up for services that require identity verification.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-4 align-items-stretch d-flex justify-content-center&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;card bg-gradient-primary&quot; style=&quot;width: 20rem;&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;card-body&quot;&gt;
            &lt;h5 class=&quot;card-title text-white&quot;&gt;Maintain identity privacy&lt;/h5&gt;
            &lt;p class=&quot;card-description text-white&quot;&gt;Control how and with who you share your identity information.&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-12 mx-auto&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h6 class=&quot;text-uppercase&quot;&gt;About problem&lt;/h6&gt;
        &lt;h3 class=&quot;display-3&quot;&gt;Why did we create idemeum?&lt;/h3&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row mt-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6 mx-auto&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;We have spent years in the identity and cyber security space, and yet we could not understand one paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;Digital identity is so critical to everything we do digitally, yet it gets compromised in almost every cyber security breach.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Every now and then we would hear the news and learn about yet another data breach where identity compromise would be at the core of it. And then we realized - we are not equipped with proper tools to protect our identity. We keep using old inefficient architectures and tools that have been invented years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote&quot;&gt;First passwords probably arrived at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in the mid-1960s.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;That is when we embraced on a journey to address the problems of &lt;strong&gt;identity privacy&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;fraud&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;passwords&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6 mx-auto&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blogs/about-idemeum/box.jpg&quot; /&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; style=&quot;flex-wrap: wrap-reverse;&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;
          &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blogs/about-idemeum/privacy.jpg&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h3 class=&quot;display-4&quot;&gt;Why idemeum enables 100% privacy&lt;/h3&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;As organizations store user accounts and credentials in centralized databases, hackers compromise these systems and release lists of usernames and passwords on the open web. We have a single point of failure that can be exploited with devastating results. The more we follow the centralized model, the more we sacrifice our privacy and security.
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Use &lt;strong&gt;social login&lt;/strong&gt; you would say? Sounds interesting, but... Are you ok with large social login providers knowing exactly when and where you log into? Knowing what services you use? It is quite a trade off - to forgo your privacy for simplicity and convenience. What is more, if your social account gets locked or disabled, you will lose access to everything you accessed with it.
        &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h3 class=&quot;display-4&quot;&gt;Why idemeum reduces fraud&lt;/h3&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Identity fraud is sophisticated and serious. Professional fraudsters work full-time, employing a range of creative and complex techniques to increase efficiencies and maximize profits. The fundamental issue is the issue of online trust - modern internet does not require user to confirm or prove one's identity.
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;As the proliferation of online services grow and enterprises undergo digital transformation, we are facing more and more cases where trust and identity verification are required. Obtaining healthcare, executing financial transactions, or opening accounts governed by KYC regulations - are all cases where identity fraud implications can be devastating.
        &lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blogs/about-idemeum/fraud.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;section&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot; style=&quot;flex-wrap: wrap-reverse;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;image-container&quot;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/blogs/about-idemeum/password.jpg&quot; /&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;col-lg-6&quot;&gt;
          &lt;h3 class=&quot;display-4&quot;&gt;Why idemeum eliminates passwords&lt;/h3&gt;
          &lt;p&gt;We have &lt;strong&gt;&quot;simple strings of characters&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; that can ruin our lives and reveal everything about us. Your email. Your bank account. Your files. Your private photos. Your location. No matter how complex, no matter how unique, our passwords can no longer protect us. We constantly try to patch passwords, but we are unsuccessful. For instance, despite the obvious benefits of &lt;strong&gt;multi-factor authentication&lt;/strong&gt;, organizations tend to leverage this technology on a selective basis. Why? Enterprises are yet to determine what IT assets require MFA, and how to deal with user experience compromises.
          &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Nikolay</name></author><summary type="html">About the name What does idemeum mean? Let's start with the name. We wanted the name of the product to reflect our mission and what we stand for. idemeum is comprised of two latin words: meum and idem that mean &quot;my&quot; and &quot;identity&quot;. We aspire idemeum to be truly yours. Something that you can own, control, and share only with people and services you choose to. And we want idemeum to be your digital identity. Not some random string of characters that is hard to remember, but your true digital identity that you can use personally and professionally. identity (n.) The word identity was first used in English by bishop and historian John Bale in 1545. Through Middle French, it all comes from the Latin neuter idem, meaning &quot;the same&quot;. Read more</summary></entry></feed>